Quirini, Helen; Papers apap102
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Community Activism, 1898-2010; Undated; 6
  - Day Care, 1953-2005; Undated; 6.3; 2.04 cubic ft.
    - Council, Clippings, 1982; 1984-1985 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 20)
    - Day Care Funding, County Statistics, Allocation and Subsidy Information, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 21)
    - Dix, Georgetta, Obituaries and Memorials, 1970-2005; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 22)
    - Department of Social Services Administrative Directives, Memos, Correspondence, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 23)
    - Department of Social Services Annual Report, 1984 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 24)
    - Department of Social Services Notice of Emergency Adoption Legislation, 1990 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 25)
    - Early Childhood Task Force - Correspondence, Agenda, Mission Statement, Meeting Minutes, Clippings, 1970-1996 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 26)
    - Employed Mothers and Child Care - U.S. Department of Labor Pamphlet, 1953 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 27)
    - Financing, Media Folder, Correspondence, Financial Information, Clippings, Pamphlets, Memos and Notes, 1978; 1980-1986; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 28)
    - Financial Records, By-Laws, Correspondence, Press Releases, Day Care Directory, Clippings, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 29)
    - Fliers, Pamphlets, 1985-1991; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 30)
    - A Forum on Child Care and Adult Care Conference Materials, Executive Summary, 1991; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 31)
    - Funding and Day Care in Schenectady, 1970-1982; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 32)
    - Handwritten Notes, 1983-1995; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 33)
    - Hearings, Testimonials, Correspondence, 1974; 1983; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 34)
    - Helen Quirini's Testimonies to Assorted Committees, Drafts, Notes, 1985-1986; 1990; 1991; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 35)
    - Human Services Planning Council - Child Care Needs Assessment for Schenectady County, 1990 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 36)
    - Initiatives Proposal - Notes, Drafts, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 37)
    - Legislation - Correspondence, Newsletters, 1982-1984; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 38)
    - Legislation - Department of Social Services, Correspondence, Clippings, Reports, Testimonies, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 39)
    - Legislation - Reports, Testimonies, Newsletters, 1983-194 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 40)
    - Legislation and Legislative Conference Reports, Correspondence, 1984; 1988; 1990; 1992 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 41)
    - Letters, Correspondence, Clippings, Notes, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 42)
    - Letters to Assemblymen in Support of Increased Day Care Funding, 1986 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 43)
    - Maps, 1986; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 44)
    - Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Notes, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 45)
    - Meeting Minutes, Resources and Needs Report, Clippings, Correspondence, 1985; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 46)
    - Newsletters, Assorted Publications on New York State Day Care, 1985-1994 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 47)
    - New York Children's Health Insurance for Lifelong Development Program Packet, Child Care Development Block Grant Draft Plan, Correspondence and Related Materials - [RESTRICTED], 1989; 1991; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 48)
    - New York State Child Care Coordinating Council- Agendas and Minutes, 1986; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 1)
    - New York State Child Care Coordinating Council and the Schenectady Day Care Council - Correspondence, Briefing Papers, Legislation Information, 1983; 1985 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 2)
    - New York State Child Care Coordinating Council - Correspondence, Financial Records, By-Laws, 1980; 1983-1986; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 3)
    - New York State Child Care Coordinating Council - Correspondence, Policies, Minutes, Conference Information, Legislation Discussion and Notes, 1985; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 4)
    - New York State Child Care Coordinating Council- Minutes, Reports, Correspondence, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 5)
    - New York State Child Care Coordinating Council - "Survey of Characteristics of Families Using Child Day Care", 1980 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 6)
    - New York State Executive Budget, Statistical and Narrative Summary of the Executive Budget, 1991; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 7)
    - New York State Senate Standing Committee on Child Care, Chairman's Report, 1986 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 8)
    - Meeting Minutes of Assorted Groups, 1993-1994; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 9)
    - Parent's Guide to Day Care Publications, 1989; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 10)
    - Personnel Reports, Minutes, Agendas, Correspondence, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 11)
    - Preschool: A Therapeutic Approach for Working with Children and their Families - Conference Sponsored by Christ Church Day Care Center, Articles, Surveys, Notes and Conference Materials, 1987-1993; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 12)
    - Public Day Care in Schenectady County; An Examination of Cost Effectiveness Issues in Four Centers Report, 1982 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 13)
    - Refreshing Springs Day Care - Audit Reports, Curriculum, Budget Material, 1980; 1992-1994; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 14)
    - Refreshing Springs Day Care - Event Program, Fact Sheet, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 15)
    - Refreshing Springs Day Care - Financial Statement, Memo and Resume for Job Application, Notes, 1989; 1994-1995; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 16)
    - Refreshing Springs Day Care - Internal Correspondence, Event Fliers, Clippings, 1970-2002; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 17)
    - Regulations and Guidelines, Reports, Resource Directory, Correspondence, 1981-1987; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 18)
    - Reports, Legislation on Reimbursement and Other Topics, 1, 1983; 1985 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 19)
    - Reports, Parent Guide to Day Care Homes Information Packet, Schenectady Department of Social Services, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 20)
    - Response to Child Care Legislation, Memorandum of Opposition, 1985; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 21)
    - Schenectady Child Care Council - Budget and Reimbursement, Correspondence, Reports, Legislation, Notes, Clippings, 1981-1991; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 22)
    - Schenectady Child Care Council - Correspondence and Packet of Requests and Suggestions Sent to the U.S. Department of Agriculture Regarding Nutrition and Budget, Notes, 1984; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 23)
    - Schenectady Child Care Council - Correspondence with U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1984; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 24)
    - Schenectady Child Care Council - Minutes, Correspondence, Budget Materials, 1984-1985; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 25)
    - Schenectady Child Care Council - Nutrition Program, Correspondence with Congressman Samuel Stratton, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Notes, Budgets, 1984; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 26)
    - Schenectady County "Annual Implementation Report of the Consolidated Services Plan," Draft, 1986 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 27)
    - Schenectady County "Annual Implementation Report of the Consolidated Services Plan," Draft, 1987 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 28)
    - Schenectady County Budget and Welfare, Correspondence, "Welfare to Work" Employment Program, 1995-1996; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 29)
    - Schenectady County Child Care Council- Correspondence with Commissioner of the Department of Social Services Richard Staszak, Budget Information, 1990-1992; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 30)
    - Schenectady County Day Care Pamphlets, Helen Quirini's Chairperson Reports, Assorted Fliers, 1970-1985; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 31)
    - Schenectady County JOBS Plan, Department of Social Services- Correspondences, Day Care Provider Instructions, 1990-1992; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 32)
    - Schenectady County Day Care Contract - Correspondence with Refreshing Springs, Christ Church Day Care Centers, Notes, Contract, 1982; 1984-1985; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 33)
    - Schenectady Day Care Council - Advisory Board, Poverty Guidelines, Budget Information, Correspondence, 1979; 1983-1985; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 34)
    - Schenectady Day Care Council and the New York Child Care Coordinating Center - Correspondence, Minutes, Annotated Drafts, Speech and Writings by Helen Quirini, 1984-1985; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 35)
    - Schenectady Day Care Council - Budget Materials, Correspondence, Minutes, 1983-1986; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 36)
    - Schenectady Day Care Council - "Child Care Services Directory", 1980; 1985 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 37)
    - Schenectady Day Care Council - Notes and Speeches, 1984-1986; 2002; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 38)
    - Schenectady Day Care Council - United Way Task Force Report on Child Care, Correspondence, Reports, Surveys, 1984-1985; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 39)
    - Schenectady Early Childhood Center Proposal- Drafts, Correspondence, Clippings, 1990-1991; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 40)
    - Something to Believe In, Refreshing Spring Day Care Center Written by Frances Grant in Collaboration with Georgetta Dix, 1973 (Oversized 18, Folder 1)
    - Staszak, Richard - Commissioner of the Department of Social Services, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 41)
    - State Funding Materials, Correspondence, Notes, Budgets, 1991-1993; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 42)
    - Statistics on Day Care Fees and Attendance, 1992-1994; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 43)
    - Testimonies to the Senate Committee on Day Care, 1985-1986 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 44)
    - Testimonies and Related Material, 1991-1993; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 45)
    - Transportation Correspondence, Notes, 1984; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 46)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - "Community Solutions for Child Care" Conference Report, 1979 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 47)
    - Welfare and Child Care - Welfare Reform, Reports, Fliers, Correspondence, 1994; 1997; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 48)
  - Schenectady County Development and Consumerism, 1969-2007; Undated; 6.4; 1.88 cubic ft.
    The materials in this subseries concern housing, energy and development in Schenectady County. Some materials were gathered by Helen Quirini in response to development plans by the Metroplex Development Authority in Schenectady County, Industrial Development Agencies (IDA) and Schenectady Economic Development Corporation (SEDC). Metroplex was created in 1998 to coordinate economic development activities. Several of Metroplex's proposals met with resistance from the public, including the proposal to tear down the Gazette Building on State and Broadway and replace it with a new Department of Transportation office building. Quirini, with others from Preserve Schenectady's Future, filed a lawsuit to save the Gazette Building. Citizens for Preservation and Revitalization (CPR) and the March 19th Coalition were organizations formed in opposition to Metroplex and its proposals. In 2002, the Glenville Energy Park was proposed and Citizens Advocating Responsible Development (CARD) petitioned against it. Quirini gathered other materials as part of activities with consumer advocacy groups. She joined Better Neighborhoods Inc. in 1971, was elected to the board in 1981 and served as president from 1984-1986. She also served on the Consumer Advisory Council of Niagara Mohawk in the late 1980s.
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., Annual Reports, 1969-1984 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 1)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., Board of Directors, 1971-1984 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 2)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., Brochures, 1970-1972; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 3)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., By-Laws, 1972 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 4)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., Correspondence, 1970-1986; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 5)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., Hamilton Hall, 1981; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 6)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., News Clippings, 1971-1994 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 7)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., Quirini Membership Certification and Bond, 1971-1977 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 8)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., Quirini Photograph, Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 9)
    - Better Neighborhoods Inc., Quirini's Notes, 1971 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 10)
    - CARD By-Laws, Meeting Agendas, and Letters, 2000-2002 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 11)
    - CARD Petition Against Glenville Energy Park, 2002 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 12)
    - City of Schenectady IDA Background Materials, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 13)
    - City of Schenectady IDA Board Meeting, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with Fred Ross, 1990-1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 15)
    - County Court House, 2001 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 16)
    - CPR Coordinating Committee, Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 17)
    - CPR Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 18)
    - CPR Mission and Members, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 19)
    - CPR News, 1998-2001 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 20)
    - CPR Petitions, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 21)
    - CPR Response to Metroplex By-Laws, 1999 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 22)
    - CPR Statement and Speeches, 1998-2003 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 23)
    - CPR Website, 1998 August 18 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 24)
    - Gazette Buildings, Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 25)
    - Gazette Buildings, Lawsuit to Save Gazette Buildings, 2000 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 26)
    - Gazette Buildings, Petitions, Flyers and Lawsuit to Save Gazette Buildings, Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 27)
    - Gazette Buildings, Photographs, 2000 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 28)
    - Housing Advocates, Catholic Charities 1983 Memorandum, Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 29)
    - IDA Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 30)
    - IDA Fiscal Policy Institute, 1992-1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 31)
    - IDA Introduction, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 32)
    - Introduction to the Universal Utility Service Act, Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 33)
    - March 19th Coalition, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 34)
    - Metroplex, 1999 March 22 (Video-tape 101)
    - Metroplex, 1999 November 11 (Video-tape 102)
    - Metroplex, 2000 March (Video-tape 100)
    - Metroplex, 2007 February 05 (Dvd 36-37)
    - Metroplex Agenda, Meeting Minutes and Resolutions, 1999-2002 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 35)
    - Metroplex Annual Reports and Financial Statements, 2000-2001 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 36)
    - Metroplex Board Handbook, Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 37)
    - Metroplex By-Laws, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 38)
    - Metroplex, Correspondence with Senator Hugh Farley, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 39)
    - Metroplex Formation in New York Legislation, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 40)
    - Metroplex, George Robertson, 1998-2004 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 41)
    - Metroplex, IDA's, 1999 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 42-43)
    - Metroplex, Meeting Regarding Metroplex Bonding Ability, 2000 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 44)
    - Metroplex, Opposition to Formation, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 45)
    - Metroplex, Proposed Amendments, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 46)
    - Metroplex, Quirini's Application to Board, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 47)
    - Metroplex, Quirini's Notes, 2002-2004 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 48)
    - Metroplex, Robert Schulz, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 49)
    - New York State Coalition for Action on Home Energy, Undated (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 50)
    - New York State Consumer Protection Board, 1997 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 51)
    - News Clippings, Brandywine Industrial Park, 1999 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 52)
    - News Clippings, Gazette Building, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 53)
    - News Clippings, Glenville Power Plant, 2002 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 54)
    - News Clippings, IDA, 1989-2002 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 55)
    - News Clippings, Metroplex Cartoon, 1998 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 56)
    - News Clippings, Schenectady Redevelopment, 1998 January-1998 June (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 57)
    - News Clippings, Schenectady Redevelopment, 1998 July-1998 December (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 58)
    - News Clippings, Schenectady Redevelopment, 1999 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 59)
    - News Clippings, Schenectady Redevelopment, 2000-2006 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 60)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Annual Report, 1990-1993 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 61)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Century Wagon School Safety Program, 1986 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 62)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Consumer Advisory Council Meeting Minutes and Notes, 1984-1989 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 1)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Consumer Advisory Council Ten Year Report, 1977-1988 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 2)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Consumer Affairs Department Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 3)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Frontier Region Bi-Monthly Reading, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 4)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Fuel Adjustment Clause Intervention by Local 301, IUE and other Unions, 1982 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 5)
    - Niagara Mohawk, News Clippings, 1983-1994 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 6)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Petition Against Pilot Light Services, 1999; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 7)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Power Choice Settlement Correspondence, Resolution and News Clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 8)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Power Choice Settlement Petition, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 9)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Power Choice Settlement, Reaction from Seniors, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 10)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Publication, 1985-1989 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 11)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Reducing Plan, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 12)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Self-Assessment Plan Summary, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 13)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Summary of News Clippings, 1988-1992 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 14)
    - Niagara Mohawk, Wurlitzer Service Study, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 15)
    - NYPIRG Citizen Alliance, Gas Bill Press Release, 1983 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 16)
    - Petition to Rescind County Sales Tax, 2001 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 17)
    - Power Plant, Certification Review Process for Major Electric Generating Facilities, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 18)
    - Power Plant, Connect the Dot a Common Cause Publication, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 19)
    - Power Plant, Correspondence, 2002 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 20)
    - Power Plant, Quirini's Notes, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 21)
    - Schenectady, 2000 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 22)
    - Schenectady County Economic Development Advisory Board Action Plan, 1997-1998 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 23)
    - Schenectady County IDA Meeting Agendas and Reports, 1999-2002 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 1)
    - Schenectady County Legislature Agendas, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 2)
    - Schenectady Downtown Redevelopment, Previous Plans, 1974; Undated (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 3)
    - Schenectady Economic Development Corporation, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 4)
    - Schenectady Master Planning Process, 1998-2002 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 5)
    - Schenectady New York Downtown Development Plan, 1970 (Oversized 3, Folder 5)
    - Task Force on Alternative Housing, Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 6)
    - Telephone Service, Petition, Letters and Bills, 1996-2002 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 7)
    - Western Gateway Transportation Center, Correspondence and News Clippings, 1998-2002 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 8)
  - Senior Citizens, 1972-2010; Undated; 6.5; 4.53 cubic ft.
    During her retirement, Helen Quirini was extremely active in many organizations for senior citizens on local, statewide and national levels. In addition to work on behalf of the GE Retirees, she served for many years as president of Chapter 490 (Schenectady County) of the American Association of Retired Persons (AARP) and as president of the Schenectady County Council of Senior Organizations. The files contain meeting minutes, events materials, financial records, correspondence, newsletters and petitions from these two groups.
    Her participation in the Schenectady County Council of Senior Organizations led in 1987 to her involvement with the StateWide Senior Action Council. Quirini served as an at-large board member and later as treasurer of StateWide. She received the Rose Kryzak Advocacy Award as a leader on public policy issues, both locally and statewide. A grassroots organization composed of individual senior citizens and senior citizen clubs from across New York, StateWide is involved in legislative issues and campaigned against Medicare cuts and mandatory retirements. The group fought for pharmaceutical insurance for the elderly, assistance for seniors with utility payments and greater protection of hospital patient rights. The files reflect StateWides advocacy activities and feature testimony, including Quirinis, before legislative panels and materials from an annual Grassroots Senior Citizens Day which encouraged seniors to come to Albany to meet with elected representatives. There also are board meeting minutes, correspondence, convention booklets and materials from Quirinis local chapter of the organization.